Guide to the Michael Polanyi Papers 1900-1975
University of Chicago Library
Juro Horiuchi, 1934 Dec. 13. 1935 Feb. 4; Mar. 17, 20; Apr. 24; July 30; Aug. 29; Oct. 25. 1936 Jan. 13; July 3, 10. 1956 May 15. 2 n.d.
Robert M. Hutchins, 1964 Dec. 30.
Sir Christopher Ingold, 1934 Apr. 24, 30; Nov. 7, 8. 1935 Dec. 15. 1936 Mar. 28; Nov. 6. 1938 Jan. 11, 14, 17. 1939 May 16, 18; Sept. 28. 1940 June 13. 1941 Jan. 22; Feb. 5. 1942 June 10. 1946 Nov. 20, 21, 25, 29. 1947 July 9.
Oscar Jászi, 1935 Nov. 24. 1936 Aug. 22. 1937 Sept. 2. 1938 Jan. 3. 1939 Apr. 24. 1940 May 9; July 22; Sept. 20. 1941 Mar. 23; July 29. 1942 Dec. 20. 1944 Apr. 28; May 1, 27; July 5. 1945 Mar. 28; July 22; Oct. 12. 1946 Feb. 28. 1947 July 28; Aug. 22. 1948 Apr. 4; Dec. 15. 1949 Dec. 25. 1950 Nov. 27. 1952 Apr. 29. 1955 Oct. 14. 2 n.d.
Konstantin A. Jelenski, 1966 Feb. 11. 1969 June 27; July 15, 20, 31; Aug. 20, 26; Sept. 1, 3, 4, 8, 15, 17, 29; Oct. 7, 9, 13, 21. 1970 Aug. 10; Nov. 27. 1971 Oct. 14; Nov. 1; Dec. 30. 1972 Jan. 7; Feb. 7, 9, 11, 14, 21, 24; Mar. 1, 9, 13, 30; Apr. 3; May 30; June 5, 12, 25; July 31; Aug. 21. 1975 Jan. 16, 20; Mar. 17.
John Jewkes, 1936 Feb. 6, 11, 12; July 20; Dec. 7. 1937 Feb. 3. 1938 Dec. 13. 1939 Oct. 23. 1940 Feb. 7. 1941 June 27. 1943 Feb. 8. 1944 Jan. 10; Apr. 18. 1946 Nov. 18. 1947 May 7. 1948 May 5; "monday" [no month or day.] 1952 Dec. 1. 3 n.d.
Abram Joffé, 1935 July 5.
David Caradog Jones, 1942 Mar. 20, 31; Apr. 2. 1943 Jan. 30; Feb. 4, 12, 18; Mar. 20, 22.
Michael Josselson, 1969 Apr. 14, 21; May 1, 13; Aug. 25. 1970 Nov. 18; Dec. 4. 1971 Apr. 29; June 14; July 13; Nov. 4, 10. 1972 June 29; July 23; Sept. 14; Oct. 19.
Bertrand de Jouvenal, 1972 Jan. 12.
Ivan Kats, 1960 Nov. 7, 8, 9, 10, 12, 18, 21, 22.
Edwin C. Kemble, 1947 Mar. 7; Apr. 16.
John Maynard Keynes, 1940 Feb. 6, 8, 19. 1945 Dec. 20; 1946 Feb. 23.
Frank Knight, 1948 Feb. 11; June 16.
Sigmund Koch, 1971 Jan. 7.
Arthur Koestler, 1941 May 15, 18, 23; June 1; July 12; Aug. 8, 13. 1942 Mar. 5; Apr. 26; July 8; Aug. 21. 1943 Jan. 25; Apr. 2; June 12; July 17; Aug. 5, 27; Sept. 1; Dec. 16. 1944 Jan. 10. 1946 Mar. 3, 15; Apr. 26, 30; May 21, 24; June 22; July 22; Aug. 29; Oct. 22; Nov. 14. 1947 Jan. 20, 22; Aug.14, 19. 1949 May 26. 1962 Mar. 8. 1967 Nov. 4. 1968 Oct. 14. 1969 Sept. 4, 17. 1970 Aug. 4. 1971 Dec. 16, 22. 1972 Jan. 13. 1973; Apr. 9. 4 n.d.
Elmer Kohler, 1935 Nov. 8, 21.
Nicholas Kurti, 1968 Sept. 7, 9. 1970 Nov. 11. 1972 May 14, 18. 1974 Jan. 7.
Imre Lakatos, 1969 Dec. 2, 5, 11. 1970 Jan. 28; Mar. 12. 1972 July 31; Aug. 24, 31.
Melvin Lasky, 1965 Mar. 3. 1967 Nov. 6. 1969 Sept. 16, 26; Oct. 9, 15, 20. 1970 June 2, 22, 24, 25; July 27. 1971 May 6.
Max von Laue, 1936 May 3, 13.
Wolfgang Leonhard, 1957 July 9, 15, 17.
Maurice Letort, 1945 Oct. 23.
P. A. Levene, 1935 Feb. 25.
W. Arthur Lewis, 1 n.d.
Samuel C. Lind, 1937 Feb. 8, 18.
Robert Livingston, 1934 Oct. 5.
Dame Kathleen Lonsdale, 1946 Nov. 27, 28.
Leo Lowenthal, 1963 Apr. 2.
Karl Mannheim, 1944 Jan. 10, 14; Feb. 1; Apr. 19, 26; May 2, 10, 27; June 13, 27, 29; July 27; Aug. 10, 16; Oct. 2, 23, 27. 1945 Jan. 1, 15; Mar. 6, 9; Apr. 12; May 23, 25, 26; Aug. 8, 17; Sept. 14, 18.
Hermann Mark, 1932 Dec. 23. 1933 Apr. 28; June 16; Aug. 16. 1934 Apr. 25. 1973 July 8.
Jacob Marshak, 1943 Aug. 31. 1948 Mar. 3, 23. 1973 Apr. 24; May 15; June 4; Dec. 18.
Abraham and Bertha Maslow, 1969 June 23. 1970 Oct. 5. 1971 Apr. 21; May 17. 1972 Mar. 9, 30; Apr. 11, 17, 24; July 5, 13, 19, 24; Aug. 2, 8; Oct. 2.
Wolfe Mays, 1969 June 28; July 9. 1970 Feb. 17, 19; Mar. 20; Apr. 3. 1973 Dec. 4, 31.
Eugen Merzbacher, 1964 May 2.
Otto Meyerhof, 1930 Mar. 23. 1932 Feb. 4. 1934 June 7. 1935 Mar. 13. 1936 Feb. 19. 1938 Aug. 30. 1939 Apr. 11. 1940 Feb. 13; Dec. 25. 1941 June 19; 1943 Dec. 10; 1944 January. 2 n.d.
Daniel P. Moynihan, 1968 May 7. 1969 June 2, 12. 1970 Jan. 19; Apr. 13, 20; July 2; Oct. 15; Nov. 3, 27; Dec. 1.
Michael Murphy, 1970 Mar. 3, 10.
Sir Lewis Namier, 1934 May 27; July 7.
Walter H. Nernst, 1913 Aug. 22, 30; Sept. 3; Oct. 15. 1914 Feb. 17. 1924 July 14.
Maxwell Newman, 1949 Sept. 19.
Ronald Norrish, 1938 Dec. 5.
Ivan Obreimov, 1 n.d.
Friedrich Paneth, 1920 Feb. 27; July 11; Oct. 27.
Maurice Pirenne, 1967 Sept. 6. 1968 July 17, 19. 1969 June 13; Aug. 23; Oct. 29; Nov. 7, 20, 21, 25, 28; Dec. 11. 1970 Jan. 16, 21; June 12, 25; July 17. 1971 Aug. 14, 31; Sept. 17. 1972 Oct. 25, 30. 1973 Mar. 15; May 30; Oct. 29; Nov. 1, 19. 1974 Sept. 10.
George Polya, 1945 Dec. 13. 1946 June 14; Oct. 21; Nov. 12. 1947 July 1. 1948 Sept. 27. 1969 Feb. 4, 11, 26; Apr. 6; Oct. 23.
Karl Popper, 1949 Oct. 11.
Oscar Rice, 1935; Nov. 6, 27.
Sir Eric Rideal, 1937 Dec. 1. 1939 May 9; Nov. 10, 14. 1940 May 31; June 1. 1942 Apr. 10. 1971; July 2, 13.
Sir Robert Robinson, 1933 Nov. 8. 1940 Jan. 11; Apr. 29. 1946 Feb. 12.
Carl Rogers, 1964 Jan. 1. 1968 Feb. 21; Aug. 29; Sept. 26; Dec. 31. 1969 Nov. 8, 15.
Peter Scheffler, 1963 Feb. 15
Edwin Schrödinger, 4 n.d.
Nicolai Semenoff, 1930 Feb. 15. 1931 Dec. 17. 1932 Mar. 1; Apr. 12. 1934 May 15; June 13; Aug. 11. 1935 Jan. 9; Mar. 21. 2 n.d.
Edward Shils, 1947 Sept. 8. 1955 Dec. 17 1957 June 4; Oct. 23. 1968 Dec. 6. 1969 Dec. 10. 1971 Oct. 19. 1972 Jan. 10, 13, 20, 31; Feb. 2, 8; July 18, 26; Aug. 20. 1973 Aug. 30; Sept. 17. 1 n.d.
Adolf Smekal, 1921 Nov. 21. 1922 Mar. 13; Apr. 7; May 8; June 29; Oct. 14.
C. P. Snow, 6 n.d.
Otto Stern, 1928 Oct. 10.
Shepard Stone, 1967 Dec. 11. 1968 Apr. 19; May 1, 31. 1969 May 6; June 10; July 9. 1970 Jan. 19, 22, 28.
Rex Stout, 1970 Apr. 27; June 17.
Leo Szilard, 1929 Apr. 1. 1933 Aug. 17; Dec. 11. 1934 Jan. 29; July 13. 1935 June 25. 1 n.d.
R. H. Tawney, 1943 July 1. 1944 Mar. 18.
A. J. P. Taylor, 1933 Sept. 21. 1 n.d.
Paul Tillich, 1963 May 21; June 4.
Alexander R. Todd, 1938 July 26.
Samuel Tolansky, 1942 Feb. 9, 12.
Theodore Von Karman, 1920 Mar. 17.
Sir Geoffrey Vickers, 1967 Dec. 12, 15. 1970 Jan. 30; July 5; Aug. 31; Oct. 2, 5, 7; Dec. 7, 10. 1971 Oct. 4 1972 Dec. 8. 1973 Mar. 27.
C. H. Waddington, 1960 Dec. 31. 1961 Jan. 3.
George Wald, 1964 May 30.
Sir Francis Walshe, 1956 June 17. 1957 May 11. 1963 Oct. 20, 26. 1964 Nov. 27. 1969 Aug. 1, 4. 1970 Sept. 16, 19; Oct. 5; Nov. 6, 13. 1971 Mar. 10.
Otto Warburg, 2 n.d.
Marx Wartofsky, 1969 July 29. 1971 June 21.
Dame Veronica Wedgwood, 1956 July 24. 1962 Sept. 23. 1963 Sept. 27. 1966 Oct. 2. 1970 May 14. 1972 July 19, 25; Aug. 8. 1973 Oct. 5. 7 n.d.
Sir Vincent Wigglesworth, 1972 Oct. 12, 19, 25.
Eugene Wigner, 1932 Oct. 18. 1933 Feb. 2; Apr. 13; June 25, 30; July 31; Oct. 7; Nov. 6. 1934 Jan. 12, 13; Apr. 7, 14; June 27; July 2; Aug. 3; Sept. 27. 1936 Dec. 8. 1937 June 23; Sept. 6; Oct. 5. 1938 Sept. 25. 1939 Sept. 19. 1940 Sept. 1. 1961 Apr. 3; June 20. 1962 Dec. 17. 1965 Dec. 30. 1966 Jan. 4, 5, 7, 8, 11, 18. 1968 Mar. 24. 1969 Sept. 4, 20. 1970 Jan. 26; Feb. 2; Mar. 23; Apr. 7; Nov. 2, 11; Dec. 15. 1971 Feb. 4; Mar. 16, 22; Apr. 24; May 3; Dec. 14, 16. 1972; Feb. 21; Mar. 4; Apr. 18; Dec. 2. 1973 June 14; July 28; Sept. 23; Oct. 25; Nov. 25. 1974 Feb. 2; Mar. 17; May 8. 10 n.d.
Dorothy Wrinch, 1935 Dec. 5.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Grene, Marjorie Glicksman, 1910-; Koestler, Arthur, 1905-; Mannheim, Karl, 1893-1947.; Oldham, Joseph Houldsworth, 1874-1969; Polanyi, Michael, 1891-1976-; Prosch, Harry, 1917-; Shils, Edward, 1910-1995.; Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902-; Keynes, John Maynard, 1883-1946; Born, Max, 1882-1970; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Szilard, Leo; Committee on Science and Freedom; Congress for Cultural Freedom; Photographs; Diaries; Sound recordings
INVENTORY
- Series I: Correspondence
  This series includes all letters in the collection written to and by Michael Polanyi, Magda Polanyi, and Cecile Polanyi. The correspondence is arranged chronologically with undated letters organized alphabetically by correspondent at the end of the series. There are two folders of unidentified, undated correspondence and fragments following the identified undated correspondence (14:13-14). Letters from John R. Baker, Marjorie Grene, Joseph H. Oldham, Julius and Elsa Hollo, Harry Prosch, Karl and Ilona Polanyi, and Cecile Polanyi have been separately arranged (Boxes 14-20).
  The correspondence in the Polanyi Papers amply documents the development of his scientific researches. His early scientific studies of adsorption and reaction kinetics are mentioned in several letters from the 1917-1919 period (1:5). In the autumn of 1920, he joined the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute; until 1933, when Polanyi left Berlin, he corresponded regularly with many of the leading scientists of Germany (1:6-2:15) and the larger European community (including James Franck, Otto Hahn, Werner Heisenberg, Wilfred Heller, and Leo Szilard.)
  - Subseries 1: General
    - 1900-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1920, Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1920, Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1920, May (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1920, June (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1920, July-Sept (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1920, Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1920, Dec (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1921, Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1921, Apr-June (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1921, July-Sept (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1921, Oct-Dec (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1922, Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1922, May-Oct (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1922, Nov-1923, May (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1923, June-Dec (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1924, Jan-July (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1924, Aug-1925, Dec (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1932, Jan-May (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1932, June-Oct (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1932, Nov-Dec (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1933, Jan-Apr (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1933, May-Aug (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1933, Sept-Dec (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1934, Jan-Feb (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1934, Mar-Apr (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1934, May-June (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1934, July-Aug (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1934, Sept-Dec (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1935, Jan-Apr (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1935, May-July (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1935, Aug-Oct (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1935, Nov-Dec (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1936, Jan-June (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1936, July-Dec (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1937, Jan-Apr (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1937, May-Oct (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1937, Nov-Dec (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1938, Jan-May (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1938, June-Sept (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1938, Oct-Dec (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1939, Jan-Mar (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1939, Apr-June (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1939, July-Sept (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1939, Oct-Dec (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1940, Jan-Mar (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1940, Apr-July (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1940, Aug-Dec (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1941, Jan-June (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 1941, July-Dec (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 1942, Jan-Oct (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 1942, Nov-1943, Mar (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 1943, Apr-Dec (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 1944, Jan-Oct (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 1944, Nov-1945, May (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 1945, June-Dec (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 1946, Jan-May (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1946, June-Dec (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1947, Jan-June (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1947, July-Dec (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 1960, Jan-Oct (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 1960, Nov-Dec (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 1961 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1963, Jan-Sept (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1963, Oct-Dec (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1964, Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1964, June-Dec (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1967, Jan-Apr (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1967, May-Dec (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1968, Jan (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1968, Feb-Mar (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 1968, Apr (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 1968, May (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 1968, June (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1968, July (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 1968, Aug (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1968, Sept (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1968, Oct (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 1968, Nov (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1968, Dec (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1969, Jan-Feb (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1969, Mar-Apr (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 1969, May (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 1969, June 1-9 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - 1969, June 10-30 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 1969, July (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 1969, Aug 1-19 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - 1969, Aug 20-31 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1969, Sept (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - 1969, Oct 1-14 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - 1969, Oct 15-31 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1969, Nov (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1969, Dec (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1970, Jan (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1970, Feb 1-11 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1970, Feb 12-28 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1970, Mar (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1970, Apr (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1970, May (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1970, June, 1-17 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 1970, June 18-30 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - 1970, July (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 1970, Aug (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 1970, Sept (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - 1970, Oct (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - 1970, Nov 1-16 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1970, Nov 17-24 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1970, Nov 25-31 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1970, Dec 1-11 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1970, Dec 12-31 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1971, Jan (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1971, Feb (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1971, Mar (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1971, Apr (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1971, May 1-10 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1971, May 11-31 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1971, June (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1971, July (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1971, Aug 1-19 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1971, Aug 20-31 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1971, Sept 1-13 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1971, Sept 14-30 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1971, Oct (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1971, Nov (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1971, Dec 1-9 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1971, Dec 10-31 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1972, Jan (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1972, Feb (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 1972, Mar 1-8 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - 1972, Mar 9-31 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1972, Apr (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - 1972, May (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - 1972, June (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1972, July (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1972, Aug 1-10 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 1972, Aug 11-31 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 1972, Sept (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 1972, Oct 1-10 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1972, Oct 11-31 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1972, Nov 1-15 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - 1972, Nov 16-30 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 1972, Dec 1-14 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 1972, Dec 15-31 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 1973, Jan (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - 1973, Feb 1-16 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1973, Feb 17-23 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1973, Feb 24-28 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1973, Mar (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1973, Apr (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1973, May (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1973, June (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1973, July (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1973, Aug (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1973, Sept (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1973, Oct (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1973, Nov (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1973, Dec (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1974, Jan (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1974, Feb 1-18 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1974, Feb 19-28 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1974, Mar 1-24 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1974, Mar 25-31 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - 1974, Apr (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 1974, May-June (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1974, July-Aug (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - 1974, Sept-Oct (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - 1974, Nov-Dec (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - A-D, no date (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - E-F, no date (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - G-H, no date (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Julius and Elsa Hollo (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Julius and Elsa Hollo (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - I-O (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Pa-Polanyi (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Pollacsek-Pz (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Q-S (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Laura Polanyi Striker (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Szecsi (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - T-Z (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified and fragments (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: John R. Baker and the Society for Freedom in Science
    - 1941-1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Announcements, manuscripts, and offprints (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Joseph H. Oldham and the "Moot"
    - 1940-1947 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1952-1964 and no date (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts for presentation at meetings of the Moot, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Manuscripts for presentation at meetings of the Moot, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Manuscripts for presentation at meetings of the Moot, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts for presentation at meetings of the Moot, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts for presentation at meetings of the Moot, no date (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4: Marjorie Grene and the Unity of Knowledge Group
    - 1953-1967 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1968, Jan-Apr (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1968, May-Dec (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - No date (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 5: Harry Prosch
    - 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - 1972 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 1973 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 1974-1975 and no date (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Manuscripts and offprints (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 6: Karl and Ilona Polanyi
    - 1913-1917 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1918-1923 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1924-1929 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1930-1933 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 1938 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 1939 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1944-1949 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - No date (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - No date (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - No date (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Karl Polanyi, clippings and obituaries (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 7: Cecile Polanyi
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Memorabilia of Cecile Polanyi (unsorted) (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Series II: Notes
  The Notes are divided into subject and author sections. The subject notes have been drawn together from materials originally labeled "miscellaneous" by Professor Polanyi's secretary. They have been organized topically and placed in alphabetical order. The author notes are compilations of quotes by and commentaries on authors whose work interested Polanyi. All of the author notes are grouped together and are arranged alphabetically by last name.
  - Subseries 1: Subject
    - Art (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Communism (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Culture (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Cybernetics (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Economics (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Formalization (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Heuristics (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Imagination (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Integration (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Knowledge (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Liberty (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Literature (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Logic (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Meaning (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - The Mind (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - The Mind (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Myth (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Neurology and psychiatry (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Perception (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Psychology (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Reality (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Religion and theology (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Science-misc. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Scientific discovery (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Scientific knowledge (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Scientific organization (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Scientific planning and development (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Scientific responsibility (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Thought (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Syllabus on unspecifiable elements of knowledge (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Syllabus on unspecifiable elements of knowledge (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Washington notes, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 2: Author
    - A, Lord Acton D. K. Adams John Couch Adams C. K. Allen E. N. Da Costa Andrade Agnes Arber Aristotle Kenneth Arrow Association of Scientific Workers R. J. C. Atkinson St. Augustine A. J. Ayer (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - B, Walter Bagehot John D. Baker Robert H. Baker Michael Balint Lawrence Balls Owen Barfield J. Baron William Barrett Carl Barth Charles Baudelaire A. G. Baumgarten Bertrand Beaumont Carl Becker Ruth Benedict Jeremy Bentham Charles Berg George Berkeley Isaiah Berlin (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - B, A. Bethe Ernst Bevin Ludwig Bieberbach Max Black H. J. Blackham Brand Blanshard E. G. Boring Franz Borkenau Max Born Bernard Bosanquet J. Bradford James Braid Lord Brain John Brennan Franz Brentano Percy W. Bridgman Crane Brinton (Box 23, Folder 3)